

Vinaya Rathod

PO Manager / Pricing Analyst



Phone +91 9699557152



mail

vinaya.rathod8800@gmail.com



Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vinaya-rathod-3aa3a3120/



Address

229, 3rd floor, 3rd Cross, Jakkasandra, 1st Block, Koramangala, 560034, Bangalore

About Me

An Astute and result oriented professional with experience in Procurement and Projects, Global Sourcing with track record of significant achievement to include reducing costs, improving quality, resulting in profits, developing & improving purchasing programs to meet corporate objectives.

Work Experience

PO Manager / Pricing Analyst

Aryaka Networks Inc., Bangalore, India

04/11/2019 - Current

- Managed quoting for New logos by providing multiple bandwidth, technology and carrier options for each site and
 Change Requests (new sites for existing customers, upgrade, migration, renewal, relocation and site decommission).
- Managed Telecom Procurement of data connectivity services (Data Business) for Enterprise Customers and Wholesale customers globally throught RFP/RFQ/ANP. Mainly worked on Access products, Internet (DIA,ADSL,SDSL& VDSL).
- Quoting process strictly followed, ensuring correct vendor selection in a BID based on factors like (MSA, Local incumbent, Services, Offer Competitiveness) and correct product as per the customer requirement.
- Responsible for cost analysis and in investigating best solution for the customer site; with diversity/or as per
 Technical consultants and Customer requirement.
- Analyzing the business performance, including the profitability, revenue, pricing, and cost of service sold.
- Vendor management, Strategic planning and negotiation.
- o Working closely with Finance to help them in case of any dispute.
- o Approve and examine PO before placing any order and keeping track of all the PO.

Quote Owner

16/05/2019 - 30/11/2019

Orange Business Services, Mumbai, India

- Responsible for IS (integrated services) quoting, that is hardware quoting professional.
- Been a focal point for quotations and customer requests and day-to-day account activities in order to maintain and enhance strong customer relationships.
- Captured and refined customer's requirements through narrow down process, using budgetary quotations when required.
- Documented Quotations into the quotation tool in support of account management as required, retrieved and documented all commercial & pricing data.
- Collaborated with vendors on key deals and to obtained preferential margins- knowledge of vendor rebate and promotional programs.

Pricing Analyst

Reliance Global Cloud Xchange, Navi Mumbai, India

- o Managing Quote to Order management.
- Taking care of Europe & India off-net pricing, working for most privileged customers of GCX and responsible for providing all possible solutions within time as per sales and technical team requirements.
- Skilled in IRU Deals, RFQ/RFP, ANP, International connectivity. Have knowledge and experience of all Layer 1,
 Layer 2 & Layer 3 products and strategic sourcing skill.
- Work on negotiations with vendors as per current market standard which helps a lot to grab new busines and new logos. End to end procurement process, negotiation, PO release, contract management & vendor performance.
- Coordinating with sales to understanding whole requirement of clients, delivering desired solution and supporting ordering team to ensure safe delivery.

Education and Training

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Telecommunication

Dr Dy Patil's Ramrao Adik Institute Of Technology, Navi Mumbai

Diploma

Veermata Jijabai Technological Institute (VJTI)

01/04/2010 - 30/03/2013

01/04/2013 - 30/05/2016

01/10/2016 - 30/04/2019

Organisational Skills

- o Ability to identify issues and areas for improvement through analysis.
- o Experience in Quote, supply chain and order management.
- Ability to manage both internal and customer relationships.
- o Excellent leadership qualities, Team orientated, with strong Relationship and Interpersonal skills.
- o Advanced negotiation, influencing and stakeholder management abilities.
- o Strong written and verbal communication skills.

Honours and Awards

- Rewarded as Best Employee at Star Awards 2016-2017 for Commendable Performance held at Reliance Global com(GCX).
- Received Best Employee in Oct-2019 in Orange.
- o Received Gold and Silver award for 3 quarters in Aryaka.

Extra Curricular Achievements

01/01/2007 - 01/08/2021

- Participated and won first position in Dance competition in year 2018 and 2019 held at Orange Business services.
- o Participated and won First position in group dance competition held at college festival 2014(VJTI).
- o Participated and awarded as best model in fashion show competition held at college festival 2014(VJTI).

Language Skills

Mother Tongue(s):

Other Language(s):

Marathi

English

Listening C2 Reading C2 Writing C2 Spoken Production C2 Spoken Interaction C2

Hindi

Listening C2 Reading C2 Writing C2 Spoken Production C2 Spoken Interaction C2